Inventory of Half a Century of Communist Cadre Training records
Hoover Institution Archives
Half a Century of Communist Cadre Training records
1966-1972
2011C32
Hoover Institution Archives
18 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (7.2 linear feet)
Sound recordings and transcripts of proceedings, and correspondence, memoranda, and conference papers, preparatory to and resulting from the conference, relating to international communist party cadre selection and leadership training.
Half a Century of Communist Cadre Training (Conference: 1969: University of South Carolina)
Walker, Richard Louis, 1922-
Lundquist, Darrel W.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2011.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
Richard L. Walker, director of the Institute of International Studies at the University of South Carolina, in 1966 conceived the idea of a conference at which veterans of leadership training schools of the Communist International and of communist parties in the Soviet Union, China and other countries might discuss and compare their experiences. The idea was approved by university officials and funding secured from the Carthage Foundation. Darrel W. Lundquist was selected as project manager for the conference, working under the general supervision of Walker. The process of selecting and inviting potential conference participants began in 1967. More than 200 potential participants were identified and considered. In addition to former communists who had gone through communist cadre training programs, these included academic experts on comparative communist systems and even a few active communists. Many candidates were contacted and responded through correspondence or by granting interviews to Lundquist, who traveled extensively for this purpose. Some who could not attend submitted written accounts of their experiences.
The conference, under the title Half a Century of Communist Cadre Training, was finally held on the University of South Carolina campus at Columbia from September 9 to 13, 1969. Thirty-two participants attended, of whom twenty-one had had personal experience as students in communist party schools in the Soviet Union, China, Poland, Hungary, North Korea, Cuba, Germany, France, Italy or the United States, while eleven were noted academic authorities on communism. Conference proceedings included both general sessions and smaller discussion group sessions. Plans were made to edit some of the conference talks and other papers submitted for publication. Efforts to arrange publication continued until at least 1972, but were never realized.
The conference records were deposited at the Heritage Foundation, from whence they were acquired by the Hoover Institution in 2011.
Scope and Content of Collection
The conference records fall into two series-- Proceedings of the conference proper, and Supporting Documents. The Proceedings consist of tape recording transcripts of both the general sessions of the conference and of the smaller group discussions. These are fairly raw; they have been edited only lightly.
The Supporting Documents include a large numerical file of potential participants. The basis for the numerical order of listing is not readily apparent and may be arbitrary. The contents of the 246 individual files composing the series vary greatly. Some consist only of biographical notes about the file's subject or unanswered letters of invitation. In other cases there is substantive correspondence, a substantive summary of an interview with the individual, and/or a substantive written memoir or conference paper. The files of many of the persons who were contacted but did not actually attend the conference nevertheless contain very significant material. Those contacted included North Americans, Latin Americans, Europeans, Africans, Asians and Australians, whose collective experience covered communist party activities from throughout the world from the 1920s to the 1960s. Most of the leading academic authorities on communism internationally as of 1969 were contacted in conjunction with the conference project, and many of their files also contain significant input.
Over all, between the Proceedings and the Supporting Documents, the quantity and range of material assembled on the specific subject of international selection and training of cadre by communist parties is unparalleled and perhaps unique.
There is some redundancy in the collection in the form of duplicate photocopies of most items.
It is not clear when or by whom the computer disks were created. The statistical and comparative data they contain is keyed to the numerical file material by file number.
Communist education.; Communist party work.; Audiotapes.
- Proceedings, 1969 (Boxes 1-3)
  Scope and Contents note
  Program, list of participants, and transcripts.
  - Program (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - List of participants (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Preliminaries (Box-folder 1: 3)
    Introductory remarks by Thomas F. Jones, president of the University of South Carolina, with French translation; opening statement by Richard L. Walker, director of the Institute of International Studies
  - Transcripts of general proceedings (Box-folder 1: 4-6)
  - Transcripts of Discussion Group 1 proceedings (Box-folder 1: 7, 2: 1)
  - Transcripts of Discussion Group 2 proceedings (Box-folder 2: 2-3)
  - Transcripts of Discussion Group 3 proceedings (Box-folder 2: 4, 3: 1)
  - Transcripts of Discussion Group 4 proceedings (Box-folder 3: 2-3)
- Supporting Documents, 1966-1972 (Boxes 3-18)
  Prospectuses, lists, correspondence, notes, conference papers, press coverage, and miscellany.
  - Prospectuses, 1967 (Box-folder 3: 4)
    Includes French and Spanish translations
  - Fundraising correspondence with Carthage Foundation (Richard M. Scaife), 1966-1967 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Lists of prospective participants (Box-folder 4: 1-2)
  - Numerical file of prospective participants, 1967-1972
    - No. 1. Rex Alfred Mortimer (Box-folder 4: 3)
      Correspondence, resumé, and typescript "Communist Cadre Training in China, 1957"
    - No. 2. José Bullejos (Box-folder 4: 4)
    - No. 3. Tamas Aczel (Box-folder 4: 5)
      Correspondence, notes, biographical data, and untitled typescript
    - No. 4. Tibor Szamuely (Box-folder 4: 6)
      Correspondence
    - No. 7. Julián Gorkin (Box-folder 5: 1)
      Correspondence, biographical data, typescript "La formación de los cuadros comunistas internacionales," and typed translation "The Development of International Communist Cadres"
    - No. 9. Branko Lazitch (Box-folder 5: 2)
      Correspondence, typescript "Naissance et but des écoles internationales du Komintern," and typed translation "The International Comintern Schools: Their Establishment and Goal"
    - No. 10. Yüeh Sheng (Box-folder 5: 3)
      Correspondence, biographical data, and typescript "A Brief History of the Education and Training of Party Cadres by the Chinese Communist Party, 1921-1969"
    - No. 12. Annie Kriegel (Box-folder 5: 4)
      Letter of invitation only
    - No. 16. Pierre Hervé (Box-folder 5: 5)
      Notes only
    - No. 19. Ante Ciliga (Box-folder 5: 6)
      Correspondence, notes, untitled typescript in Italian, and typed English translation
    - No. 20. Foy D. Kohler (Box-folder 5: 7)
      Correspondence, and summary of conference talk
    - No. 21. Philip E. Mosely (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - No. 22. Donald W. Treadgold (Box-folder 6: 2)
      Correspondence, and typescript "The Training of Communists: Some Observations on Its Historical Development"
    - No. 23. Wolfgang Leonhard (Box-folder 6: 3)
      Correspondence and notes
    - No. 24. Anita M. Dasbach (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - No. 25. Edward Kraemer (Box-folder 6: 5)
      Summary of interview
    - No. 26. Frank S. Meyer (Box-folder 6: 6)
      Correspondence, summary of interview, and notes
    - No. 29. Will Herberg (Box-folder 6: 7)
      Letter of invitation and notes only
    - No. 30. Bella Bonoff (Box-folder 6: 8)
    - No. 32 and 354 (dual numbering). Ignazio Silone (Box-folder 6: 9)
    - No. 34. Joseph Clark (Box-folder 6: 10)
    - No. 35. Joseph R. Starobin (Box-folder 6: 11)
      Correspondence and summary of interview
    - No. 36. Bertram D. Wolfe (Box-folder 6: 12)
    - No. 37. William Lavender (Box-folder 6: 13)
      Letter of invitation, summary of interview, and notes
    - No. 40. Benjamin Odum (Box-folder 6: 14)
    - No. 41. Henri Barbé (Box-folder 6: 15)
      Typescript "L'Ecole Leniniste du Komintern et ses élèves français," and typed translation "The Leninist School of the Comintern and Its French Students"
    - No. 63. Wanda Bronska-Pompuch (Box-folder 6: 16)
      Correspondence, typescript "Meine Ausbildung in der Kommunistischen Universität für Nationale Minderheiten des Westens (KUNMS) in Moskau in den Jahren 1933-36," and typed translation "My Training at the Communist University for National Minorities of the West in Moscow between 1933-1936"
    - No. 72. Joseph Zack Kornfeder (Box-folder 7: 1)
      Typescript "Training of International Communist Cadre," correspondence with Zymund Dobbs re deceased Kornfeder, and explanatory note by Dobbs
    - No. 73/74 (inconsistent numbering). Israel Soto Barroso (Box-folder 7: 2-3)
      Correspondence, biographical data, typescript "Cincuenta años de adiestramiento de los cuadros comunistas," and untitled typed English translation
    - No. 78. Rolando Meruelo Baldarraín (Box-folder 7: 4)
      Correspondence, typescript "Notas biograficas," typescript translation "The Development and Training of a Cuban Communist," typescript "Militancia comunista en Cuba durante la decada de 1935 a 1946," and untitled typed English translation
    - No. 79. Nestor A. Moreno (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - No. 81 and 295 (dual numbering). Abdurakhman Avtorkhanov (A. Kunta) (Box-folder 8: 1)
      Correspondence and typed transcript "The Organization and Operation of Schools for Leading Political Cadres of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union"
    - No. 82. Kim Dong-man (Box-folder 8: 2)
      Correspondence and typescript "Communist Cadre Training in North Korea"
    - No. 83. John Lautner (Box-folder 8: 3)
      Correspondence and typescript "Leadership Training in the CPUSA"
    - No. 84. Heinz Lippmann (Box-folder 8: 4-5, 9: 1)
      Correspondence, typescript "Zum System der Erziehung und Auswahl sowie des Einsatzes der kommunistischen Kader in der DDR und der BRD," and typed translation "The Education and Selection, as Well as the Deployment, of the Communist Cadres in the DDR and the BRD"
    - No. 85. Keith McEwan (Box-folder 9: 2)
      Correspondence and typescript "Training of Australian Cadre in China, 1951"
    - No. 86. Paul Thalmann (Box-folder 9: 3)
      Correspondence, typescript "Bemerkungen zur Bildung der Kader in der kommunistischen Bewegung," and typed translation "Remarks on the Education of Cadres in the Communist Movement"
    - No. 88. Joop Zwart (Box-folder 9: 4)
      Correspondence and typescript "Kommunistiski Internationali Moladjest, 1929 and 1930" (in English)
    - No. 89. John Gates (Box-folder 9: 5)
      Correspondence and typescript "The Nature of Communist Education"
    - No. 90. Giulio Seniga (Box-folder 10: 1)
      Correspondence and typescript "Half Century of Formation of Communist Quadri"
    - No. 91. Mieczyslaw Maneli (Box-folder 10: 2)
      Correspondence and typescript "Institute for the Development of Politico-Scientific Cadres of the Polish United Workers' Party"
    - No. 94. Boris Souvarine (Box-folder 10: 3)
    - No. 105. Gus Hall (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - No. 113. Anita Galliussi (Box-folder 10: 5)
      Correspondence and untitled biographical typescript
    - No. 114. Michael Miller (Box-folder 10: 6)
      Correspondence, typescript "Meine Erfahrungen auf der Landesparteischule in Mecklenburg, der Parteihochschule der SED Karl Marx in Kleinmachnow und in der Kaderausbildung der SED," and typed translation "My Experience at the Land Party School at Mecklenburg, the Karl Marx High Party School at Kleinmachnow and the SED Cadre Training"
    - No. 115. Lino Ronga (Box-folder 10: 7, 11: 1)
      Correspondence, biographical data, typescipt "L'educazione ideologica nel Partito Comunista Italiano," and untitled typed English translation
    - No. 116 and 126 (dual numbering). Karl Tromsdorf (Box-folder 11: 2-3)
      Correspondence, typescript "Die Parteihochschule der KPdSU: Erfahrungen eines ehemaligen SED-Funktionärs mit dem Besuch der Parteihochschule in Moskau 1953-54," and typed translation "The Party University of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union: Experiences of a Former SED-Functionary in Connection with His Attendance at the Party University in Moscow, 1953-54"
    - No. 117. Sandor Körösi-Krizsán (Box-folder 11: 4)
      Correspondence and typescript "How Cadres for the CP of Hungary Were Trained in Soviet Russia"
    - No. 118. John Kolasky (Box-folder 11: 5)
      Correspondence, biographical data, and typescript "Two Years at the Higher Party School of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of Ukraine"
    - No. 119. Richard Löwenthal (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - No. 120. Jay Lovestone (Box-folder 12: 2)
      Correspondence, notes, and summary of interview
    - No. 121. Darrel W. Lundquist (Project Director) (Box-folder 12: 3)
      Correspondence and biographical data
    - No. 122. Kenneth D. Gott (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - No. 123. William E. Griffith (Box-folder 12: 5)
      Correspondence and typescript "Communist Cadre Training: Source, Indication and Reflection of Political Liberalization and Change"
    - No. 124. William R. Kintner (Box-folder 12: 6)
      Correspondence and typescript "The Military Aspect of Communist Cadre Training"
    - No. 125. Rodger Swearingen (Box-folder 12: 7)
    - No. 127. Hermann Weber (Box-folder 12: 8)
    - No. 128. Carola Stern (Box-folder 12: 9)
      Correspondence, biographical data, and outline for essay
    - No. 129. Janos Radvanyi (Box-folder 12: 10)
      Summary of interview and notes
    - No. 130. Erno Bernat (Box-folder 12: 11)
    - No. 132. Joseph Rex (Box-folder 12: 12)
    - No. 135. Genia Quittner-Lande (Box-folder 12: 13)
    - No. 136. Inge Bialek (Box-folder 12: 14)
    - No. 137. Kurt Müller (Box-folder 12: 15)
    - No. 138. Peter C. White (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - No. 146. William Odell Nowell (Box-folder 13: 2)
      Untitled typescript and explanatory note by Zygmund Dobbs
    - No. 147. Zygmund Dobbs (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - No. 148. Ghanshwam Mehta (Box-folder 13: 4)
    - No. 149. René Goldman (Box-folder 13: 5)
    - No. 151. Milorad M. Drachkovitch (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - No. 152. Frederick C. Barghoorn (Box-folder 13: 7)
      Correspondence, notes, and typescript "The Nationality Factor and Communist Cadre Training"
    - No. 153. Alvin J. Cottrell (Box-folder 13: 8)
    - No. 154. Bernard S. Morris (Box-folder 13: 9)
    - No. 157. Theodore Draper (Box-folder 13: 10)
    - No. 158. Arnold Beichman (Box-folder 13: 11)
    - No. 159. Seweryn Bialer (Box-folder 13: 12)
    - No. 160. Earl Browder (Box-folder 13: 13)
    - No. 161. Oliver Carlson (Box-folder 13: 14)
    - No. 162. Benjamin Mandel (Box-folder 13: 15)
    - No. 163. Joaquín Maurín (Box-folder 13: 16)
      Letter of invitation and summary of interview
    - No. 164. Carlos Manuel Pellecer (Box-folder 13: 17)
    - No. 165. Eudocio Ravines (Box-folder 13: 18)
    - No. 166. Richard C. Rowson (Box-folder 13: 19)
    - No. 167. Richard Sanger (Box-folder 13: 20)
    - No. 168. Maurice Malkin (Gabriel Temkin) (Box-folder 13: 21)
    - No. 169. Isaac Don Levine (Box-folder 13: 22)
    - No. 170. James Critchlow (Box-folder 13: 23)
    - No. 171. Gerard Ludi (Box-folder 13: 24)
    - No. 172. Jack Blake (Box-folder 13: 25)
    - No. 173. Karl Baarslag (Box-folder 13: 26)
    - No. 174. George Charney (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - No. 175. George J. Lerski (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - No. 176. Albert Vassart (Box-folder 14: 3)
      Typescript "Les écoles du Parti Communiste Français," typed translation "The Schools of the French Communist Party," typescript "L'Ecole Leniniste de Bobigny: Premier centre de formation des cadres du Parti Communiste Français," and typed translation "The Leninist School of Bobigny: First Center of Training of the Cadres of the French Communist Party"
    - No. 177. Andrew Gyorgy (Box-folder 14: 4)
    - No. 178. Harry Goldberg (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - No. 179. Frank R. Barnett (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - No. 180. Victor Alba (Box-folder 14: 7)
    - No. 181. Jules Humbert-Droz (Box-folder 14: 8)
    - No. 182. Ernst Jili (Box-folder 14: 9)
    - No. 183 and 322 (dual numbering). Frank Hardy (Box-folder 14: 10)
    - No. 184. Irving Brown (Box-folder 14: 11)
    - No. 186. Clifford Forster (Box-folder 14: 12)
    - No. 187. Gus Tyler (Box-folder 14: 13)
    - No. 188. Bella V. Dodd (Box-folder 14: 14)
    - No. 189. Eugene Lyons (Box-folder 14: 15)
    - No. 190. Alexander Dallin (Box-folder 14: 16)
    - No. 191. Ruth I. Matthews (Box-folder 14: 17)
    - No. 192. Robert J. Alexander (Box-folder 14: 18)
    - No. 193. James F. Brown (Box-folder 14: 19)
      Letter of invitation and note only
    - No. 194. Nat Ross (Box-folder 14: 20)
    - No. 195. Ira Latimer (Box-folder 14: 21)
    - No. 198. Stanley G. Payne (Box-folder 14: 22)
    - No. 200. Alexander Orlov (Box-folder 14: 23)
    - No. 201. Roger E. Kanet (Box-folder 14: 24)
    - No. 202. Carl Ross (Box-folder 14: 25)
    - No. 203. Haith Cox (Box-folder 14: 26)
    - No. 204. Fred Fine (Box-folder 14: 27)
    - No. 205. Robert Morris (Box-folder 14: 28)
    - No. 206. Edward J. Rozek (Box-folder 14: 29)
    - No. 209. Osvaldo Peralva (Box-folder 14: 30)
    - No. 210. Daniel James (Box-folder 14: 31)
    - No. 211. Jorge Prieto Laurens (Box-folder 14: 32)
    - No. 212. Joe Bermudez (Box-folder 14: 33)
    - No. 213. A. B. Shah (Box-folder 14: 34)
    - No. 214. George G. Thomson (Box-folder 14: 35)
    - No. 215. Wu Chen-tsai (Box-folder 14: 36)
    - No. 216. Andres Suarez (Box-folder 14: 37)
    - No. 217. Leila George Sikes (Box-folder 14: 38)
    - No. 218. Paul D. Bethel (Box-folder 14: 39)
    - No. 219. Arnold C. Brackman (Box-folder 14: 40)
    - No. 220. Arkady V. Belinkov (Box-folder 14: 41)
    - No. 221. Alexander Bittelman (Box-folder 14: 42)
    - No. 222. Joaquin Godoy (Box-folder 14: 43)
    - No. 223. Leszek Kolakowski (Box-folder 14: 44)
    - No. 224. H. Gordon Skilling (Box-folder 14: 45)
    - No. 225. Furet Franzwa (Box-folder 14: 46)
    - No. 226. Alan H. Belmont (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - No. 228. William E. Ratliff (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - No. 232. Miroslav Tucek (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - No. 233. Max Wullschleger (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - No. 234. Richard F. Staar (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - No. 235. Richard V. Allen (Box-folder 15: 6)
    - No. 236. Franz Michael (Box-folder 15: 7)
    - No. 237. Alexander Barmine (Box-folder 15: 8)
    - No. 238. Nikolai Khokhlov (Box-folder 15: 9)
    - No. 239. R. V. Burks (Box-folder 15: 10)
    - No. 240. Ben Gold (Box-folder 15: 11)
    - No. 241. Harry Haywood (Box-folder 15: 12)
    - No. 242. William Kruse (Box-folder 15: 13)
    - No. 243. Wilbur Jared Parkhill (Box-folder 15: 14)
    - No. 244. Karl Sklar (Box-folder 15: 15)
    - No. 245. Sandor Voros (Box-folder 15: 16)
    - No. 246. Brutus Coste (Box-folder 15: 17)
    - No. 247. Karl Sternburg (Box-folder 15: 18)
    - No. 248. Freda Utley (Box-folder 15: 19)
    - No. 249. Sam Darcy (Box-folder 15: 20)
    - No. 250. Samuel Dunchin (Box-folder 15: 21)
    - No. 251. Julius Epstein (Box-folder 15: 22)
    - No. 252. Ralph de Toledano (Box-folder 15: 23)
    - No. 253. Kenneth (surname unknown) (Box-folder 15: 24)
    - No. 254. John Hladun (Box-folder 15: 25)
    - No. 255. Kenneth Eckert (Box-folder 15: 26)
    - No. 256. Ann Burlak (Box-folder 15: 27)
    - No. 257. John Robinson (Box-folder 15: 28)
    - No. 258. Red Drummond (Box-folder 15: 29)
    - No. 259. Roy Hudson (Box-folder 15: 30)
    - No. 260. Suzanne Labin (Box-folder 15: 31)
    - No. 261. D. G. Stewart-Smith (Box-folder 15: 32)
    - No. 262. Ivan Rawluk (Box-folder 15: 33)
    - No. 263. Ivan Krushelnyckyj (Box-folder 15: 34)
    - No. 264. Lady Jane Birdwood (Box-folder 15: 35)
    - No. 265. Victor J. Lloyd (Box-folder 15: 36)
    - No. 266. John Graham (Box-folder 15: 37)
    - No. 267. J. Stetzko (Box-folder 15: 38)
    - No. 268. Ole Bjorn Kraft (Box-folder 15: 39)
    - No. 269. Ivan Matteo Lombardo (Box-folder 15: 40)
    - No. 270. George Albertini (Box-folder 15: 41)
    - No. 271. H. A. van Oort (Box-folder 15: 42)
    - No. 272. Hillel H. Ticktin (Box-folder 15: 43)
    - No. 273. A. Orlow (not Alexander Orlov) (Box-folder 15: 44)
    - No. 274. Oejeng Soewargana (Box-folder 15: 45)
    - No. 275. Paul Barton (Box-folder 15: 46)
    - No. 276. Kazimierz Laski (Box-folder 15: 47)
    - No. 278. Jan Jaroslawski (Box-folder 15: 48)
    - No. 280. Otto Skorzeny (Box-folder 15: 49)
    - No. 281. Ivan Ivanovich Minischki (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - No. 282. Madame Gaubert (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - No. 283. Bogdan Raditsa (Box-folder 16: 3)
    - No. 284. Mrs. Buber-Neumann (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - No. 285. Boris Goldenberg (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - No. 286. M. W. J. M. Broekmeijer (Box-folder 16: 6)
    - No. 287. Georg von Zimmer-Lehman (Box-folder 16: 7)
    - No. 288. Hilding Eek (Box-folder 16: 8)
    - No. 289. Kevin Devlin (Box-folder 16: 9)
    - No. 290. Leonard Schapiro (Box-folder 16: 10)
    - No. 291. Wiswa Warnatala (Box-folder 16: 11)
    - No. 292. Leopold Labedz (Box-folder 16: 12)
    - No. 293. Heinrich Schulz (Box-folder 16: 13)
    - No. 294. Robert C. Hill (Box-folder 16: 14)
    - No. 298. H. Richard Krygier (Box-folder 16: 15)
    - No. 300. Ralph T. Fisher, Jr. (Box-folder 16: 16)
    - No. 303. Luis Humberto Soto (Luis Ceres) (Box-folder 16: 17)
      Correspondence, notes, and untitled typescript in Spanish
    - No. 311. Margaret Andjus (Box-folder 16: 18)
    - No. 312. Lil Andrews (Box-folder 16: 19)
    - No. 313. Philip Bart (Box-folder 16: 20)
    - No. 314. Max Bedacht (Box-folder 16: 21)
    - No. 316. Morris Childs (Box-folder 16: 22)
    - No. 317. Moissele Clinger (Box-folder 16: 23)
    - No. 318. Howard Fast (Box-folder 16: 24)
    - No. 319. Philip Frankfeld (Box-folder 16: 25)
    - No. 320. Gil Green (Box-folder 16: 26)
    - No. 321. Robert F. Hall (Box-folder 16: 27)
    - No. 323. Michael Harrington (Box-folder 16: 28)
    - No. 324. Dorothy Healey (Box-folder 16: 29)
    - No. 325. Nathaniel Honig (Box-folder 16: 30)
    - No. 326. Irving Howe (Box-folder 16: 31)
    - No. 328. Langston Hughes (Box-folder 16: 32)
    - No. 329. Coldny Helen Kay (Box-folder 16: 33)
    - No. 330. Charles Krumbein (Box-folder 16: 34)
    - No. 331. Peter Massit (Box-folder 16: 35)
    - No. 332. Ernest Lee Moon (Box-folder 16: 36)
    - No. 333. Steve Nelson (Box-folder 16: 37)
    - No. 334. Petrov (Box-folder 16: 38)
    - No. 335. Al Richmond (Box-folder 16: 39)
    - No. 336. Rosse (Box-folder 16: 40)